MBONU CHINEDU

Full Stack Developer

\$\ +2349072168687 @ cmbonu@ymail.com \@ https://github.com/cboychinedu \$\ Lagos, NG

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

03/2022 - 02/2023

Ten Gas Development Company

Ikovi, NG

- Developed new features and enhancements for the application using React and TypeScript.
- Implemented REST APIs to connect the application to the backend services.
- · Optimized REST API calls to reduce load times resulting in a 15% increase in page speed.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure timely delivery of project milestones.
- Debugged and resolved application issues to improve user experience.

Senior Software Engineer

07/2017 - 09/2022

Indev Group Limited

Victoria Island, NG

- Designed and developed reusable software components which used in 3 different project with reducing development effort by 50%.
- · Developed new features and enhancements for the web application using React and AWS.
- · Implemented and maintained backend services using Python and PostgreSQL.
- Optimized database queries resulting in a 40% reduction in downtime.
- Implemented machine learning algorithms to improve user experience resulting in a 25% increase in engagement.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure timely delivery of project milestones.

Senior Full Stack Developer

02/2015 - 11/2017

Swap Space

UAE

- Delivered configuration management tools to track server settings for performance testing which saved 25% of initial machine setup
- Developed monitor reports that are using in-memory cache, updating the data shown to the user every 1 second
- Optimized customer resources and reduce turnaround time by 20%
- Performed root cause analysis for more than 10 issues to identify bugs and rolled out fixes to production within 24 hours.
- Developed new features and enhancements for web applications using React and SQL.
- Implemented responsive designs resulting in a 15% increase in mobile traffic.
- Collaborated with clients to gather requirements and provide technical solutions resulting in a 100% satisfaction rate.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure timely delivery of project milestones.
- Debugged and resolved application issues to improve user experience.

EDUCATION

Machine learning Engineer

02/2018 - 07/2019

The Society of Petroleum Engineers

USA

Bachelor of Science, Chemical Engineering

02/2014 - 11/2023

Nnamdi Azikiwe University

Awka, NG

ACHIEVEMENTS

30% improved query efficiency

by designing and fully revising the two largest MySQL databases

Coordinated a year-long release of a six-part platform project

with marketing, BA, QA, and sales department.

Chatbot implementation

Developed a chatbot which helped customer to reduce costs by 240% in their customer service department

SKILLS

Tools

Python · Reactjs · Javascript · Nodejs ·

HTML/CSS · Flask · Django · MongoDB ·

MySql · postgresql · JSX

Operating Systems

Unix · Solaris · Linux · Windows

STRENGTHS

🛊 Gold Medalist

Was awarded an international certification in machine learning and data analysis by SPE

★ Corporate Social Responsibility

Volunteered in the CSR team for Amadeus, organized tuition platforms for the underprivileged. Designed confluence page for book drives, etc.